{
    "id": "2d031a8f22054005a4871c7a552d4fb0",
    "title": "Reported Speech",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I advised him ......................... it.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to not do",
                "not to do",
                "not do"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5d37b8673e6543a59821482bb77e0337"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me …………….. I had finished the job.",
            "description": "We report Yes/No questions with if or whether.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b5701caa0ae34ac4a25ed3e00faedbe0"
        },
        {
            "question": "She told me ……………… careful.",
            "description": "We report imperatives with to-infinitives.",
            "answers": [
                "be",
                "to be",
                "that be"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0c6edad57bfa4ce18b89337863011806"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if I ………………. my lunch.",
            "description": "Present tenses in the direct speech change into their corresponding past tenses in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "ate",
                "have eaten",
                "had eaten"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6882346f8bbe408bbd0c040057692abc"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me ………………. going to the movies.",
            "description": "We report Yes/No questions with if or whether.",
            "answers": [
                "that I was",
                "if I was",
                "if was I"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "83abfff797bb44e186e5df56adb9fd92"
        },
        {
            "question": "The dentist suggested ……………… get a new toothbrush.",
            "description": "Suggest cannot be followed by a to-infinitive. Instead, we use a that-clause.",
            "answers": [
                "me to",
                "that I should",
                "me that I should"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6017fa5217064a58b8a4360987e6a185"
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that no one ……………… me.",
            "description": "Present tenses in the direct speech change into their corresponding past tenses in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "called",
                "have called",
                "had called"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "20f98a4e07bb48b5a1f2d27be28a88be"
        },
        {
            "question": "I requested her ………………. me.",
            "description": "We report orders and requests with a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "help me",
                "to help",
                "that help"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8d4f550f0aa049b1842656273d1f6378"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me ………………. to deserve such a cruel punishment.",
            "description": "In reported questions the subject goes before the auxiliary verb.",
            "answers": [
                "what had he done",
                "what he had done",
                "that he had done"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1048944ea8da4f48b6376b6d8b933504"
        },
        {
            "question": "He promised he …………… do it by the end of the week.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech changes into would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "488b88722da343fa8a35226cd85f58fa"
        },
        {
            "question": "He explained how ……………… the problem.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to solve",
                "I should solve",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0a36946a65c14babbe6c940f5865a69c"
        },
        {
            "question": "She said ……………. she hadn’t met me before.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "if",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d29f86e284054cc5b25b0857f54f4b56"
        }
    ]
}